Register of the Herbert Solow Papers 1924-1976
Hoover Institution Archives
Herbert Solow Papers,
1924-1976
77101
Solow, Herbert, 1903-1964
12 manuscript boxes 5 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, memoranda, depositions, clippings, and other printed matter, relating to the communist movement in the United States, the Non-Partisan Defense League, the Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trials, Soviet espionage in the United States, Whittaker Chambers and the Alger Hiss case, Zionism, the Nuremberg Trial of Major German War Criminals, 1945-1946, and post-World War II international business enterprises. Includes some papers of Sylvia Salmi Solow, 1964-1976
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1977.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Chambers, Whittaker; Hiss, Alger; Trotsky, Leon, 1879-1940; Commission of Inquiry into the Charges Made Against Leon Trotsky in the Moscow Trial; Non-Partisan Labor Defense; Communism; Communism--United States; Espionage, Russian--United States; International business enterprises; Labor movement--United States; Moscow Trials, Moscow, Russia, 1936-1937; Nuremberg Trial of Major German War Criminals, 1945-1946; War crime trials; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945--Germany; Zionism; Soviet Union; Russia (Federation); United States--Politics and government; United States--Foreign relations
Biographical Note
Herbert Solow, 1903-1964
1903, November 20 Born, New York City
1924 Bachelor of Arts (Phi Beta Kappa), Columbia College
1925 Bachelor of Letters, Columbia University, School of Journalism
1927-1929 Assistant editor, Menorah Journal
1929-1932 Assistant editor, the Encyclopedia of the Social Sciences
1940-1943 Assistant to the President, New School of Social Research
1943-1945 Contributing editor to Time magazine
1945- Editor of Fortune magazine
1961- Member, board of directors of Fortune
1964, November 26 Died
Series Description
- Biographical File, 1924-1965. (Box No. 1)
  Personal documents, college diploma, biographical data, card files, newspaper clippings, and union membership cards, arranged as listed in container list.
- Correspondence, 1924-1965. (Box No. 1-3)
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- Correspondence of Sylvia Salmi Solow, 1965-1976. (Box No. 3)
- Speeches and Writings, 1928-1965. (Box No. 3-4)
  Drafts and printed copies, arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
- Subject File, 1930-1964. (Box No. 5-12)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, lists, notes, printed matter, etc. Arranged alphabetically by either author, title or subject.
- Miscellany, 1932-1965. (Box No. 12)
Container List
- Biographical File, 1924-1965.
  - General (Box 1)
    - address lists, card files, life insurance, newspaper clippings and union membership cards.
  - Death, newspaper articles about his
  - Degrees
  - Egypt incident
  - Employment, correspondence
  - List of writings
  - Memorial Fund
  - Memorial services, pamphlet and speeches
  - Moscow Daily News
  - Resumes, letters of recommendation
  - Retirement
  - Subpoena (The People of the State of New York)
  - Sympathy, Letters of
  - Wald, Alan, Portrait of a New York Intellectual., A typewritten short biography, 69 pages
- Correspondence, 1924-1965
  - Adler, Colonel Julius Ochs (New York, NY), 1938 (Box 1)
  - American Express Company (New York, NY), 1959-1961
  - Appleget, Thomas B. (New York, NY), 1949
  - Bailey, John (Washington, DC), 1964
  - Baldwin, Roger (New York, NY), 1934-1935
  - Beard, Charles A. (New Milford, CT), 1943
  - Beard, Mary B. (New Milford, CT), 1950-1952
  - Bernays, Murray C. (New York, NY), 1945
  - Biow, Milton, H. (New York, NY), 1954
  - Bourgin, Simon (Press Camp, U.S. Forces - Austria), 1951
  - Bowles, Chester (Essex, CT), 1958
  - Brenner, Anita (San Antonio, TX), 1944
  - Brong, John H. (New York, NY), 1960-1961
  - Byoir, Carl (New York, NY), 1954
  - Chafee, Zecharian, Jr., (Cambridge, MA), 1948
  - Chamberlain, John (Washington, DC), 1946
  - Chambers, Esther (Westminister, MD), 1962
  - Chambers, Whittaker (Westminister, MD), 1938?-1956
  - Clark, John Maurice (Westport, CT), 1947
  - Cort, David (New York, NY), 1948
  - Crum, Bartley C. (New York, NY), 1954
  - Cunningham, Owen (Des Moines, IA), 1954
  - Davis, Malcolm W. (New York, NY), 1943
  - DeSilver, Margaret (Brooklyn, NY), 1938?
  - de Vabres, Donnedieu (Paris, France), 1938, 1940
  - Dewey, John (New York, NY), 1932, 1936-1938
  - Dunne, Vincent R. (Minneapolis, MN), 1937
  - Eastman, Max (New York, NY), 1944
  - Engdahl, Elizabeth L. (Paris, France), 1954
  - Enright, Joseph T. (Los Angeles, CA), 1955
  - Fadiman, C. P. (New York, NY), 1937
  - Faust Verlag (Praga, Czechoslovakia), 1934
  - Ferre, Luis A. (Ponce, Puerto Rico), 1959
  - Ferry, W. H. (New York, NY), 1957
  - Finch, George A. (Washington, DC), 1946
  - Fischer, Louis (New York, NY), 1949
  - Fisher, John (New York, NY), 1946
  - Flanders, Ralph E. (Springfield, VT), 1945-1959
  - Fleetwood, Wade B. (Miami, FL), 1954
  - Forbes, Russell (San Francisco, CA), 1956
  - Ford, Guy Stanton (Washington, DC), 1950
  - Fox, Mary (New York, NY), 1935
  - Frank, John P. (New Haven, CT), 1950-1951
  - Frank, Waldo (New York, New York) 1937
  - Frankfurter, Felix (Washington, DC), 1956, 1958
  - Freund, Max (New York, NY), 1954
  - Galbraigth, J. K. (Cambridge, MA), 1958
  - Garfield, Sidney (New York, NY), 1948
  - Gillies, Donald B. (Cleveland, OH), 1953
  - Gilpatric, Roswell (Washington, DC), 1962
  - Goldman, Albert (New York, NY), 1955
  - Haas, Robert (New York, NY), 1937
  - Halasz, Andrew (New York, NY), 1950
  - Hamilton, Fowler (Washington, DC), 1961
  - Hamilton, Frederick L. (Old Saybrook, CT), 1964
  - Harris, Reed (Washington, DC), 1953-1962
  - Harron, Robert (New York, NY), 1962
  - Hatcher, John B. (Washington, DC), 1943
  - Haydn, Hiram (New York, NY), 1948
  - Hays, Paul R. (New York, NY), 1954
  - Henderson, R. W. (Bakersfield, CA), 1936-1937
  - Heymsfeld, Ralph T. (New York, NY), 1953
  - Hoehler, Fred (n.p.), 1942
  - Hook Sidney (Stanford, CA), 1961
  - Hoover, John Adgar (Washington, DC), 1938
  - Jackson, C. D. (Washington, DC), 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Keenan, Joseph B. (Washington, DC), 1948
  - Kennedy, Robert F. (Washington, DC), 1955, 1961
  - Kenyon, Theodore W. (Essex, CT), 1962
  - Kimball, Virginia (Washington, DC), 1946
  - Konvitz, Milton R. (Ithaca, NY), 1945-1954
  - Koshland, William A. (New York, NY), 1937
  - Kunitz, Mr. (n.p.), 1933
  - Kurland, Philip B. (Chicago, IL), 1954
  - La Follette, Robert M. (n.p.), 1939
  - Le Matin (Paris, France), 1924
  - Leman, Albert N. (Washington, DC), 1955
  - Lichtfield, Edward H. (Pittsburgh, PA), 1961
  - Lipsky, Louis (New York, NY), 1931
  - Livingston, Homer J. (Chicago, IL), 1956
  - Ljungberg, Gregory (Stockholm, Sweden), 1957
  - Luce, Henry (n.p.), 1947, 1954
  - Lyon, Alfred E. (New York, NY), 1954
  - McComas, O. Parker (New York, NY), 1954
  - McDonald, John (n.p.), 1952
  - Magnes, Judah L. (n.p.), n.d.
  - Mandel, Benjamin (Washington, DC), 1960
  - Margolies, Berg (Washington, DC), 1936
  - Mason, Alpheus Thomas (Princeton, NJ), 1954
  - Mills, Edward (Washington, DC), 1956
  - Minneapolis General Drivers, Helpers, Petroleum and Inside Workers Union Local No. 574 (Minneapolis, MN), 1934
  - Mooney, Tom (San Francisco, CA), 1935-1938
  - Morgan, J. H. (London, England), 1947
  - Moscoso, Teodoro (Caracas, Venezuela), 1961
  - Mumford, Lewis (Amenia, NY), 1937
  - Naville? (Paris, France), 1937
  - Neville, Sir Robert (Uplands Park Brook, Surrey, England), 1953
  - New York City. Police Department (New York, NY), 1963
  - New York County. County Clerk (New York, NY), 1959
  - New York Herald Tribune (New York, NY), 1939
  - Newsom, Earl (New York, NY), 1954
  - Newspaper Guild of New York (New York, NY), 1939
  - Nyaradi, Nicholas (Peoria, IL), 1950-1956
  - Olney III, Warren (Washington, DC), 1954
  - Overseas Press Club of America (New York, NY), 1962
  - Packer, Herbert L. (Stanford, CA), 1962
  - Paine, Ralph D., Jr. (New York, NY), 1946-1954
  - Patterson, William L. (New York, NY), 1934
  - Petrie, B. A. (n.p.), 1954
  - Poole, DeWitt C. (Cambridge, MA), 1944-1946
  - Puckette, Charles (New York, NY), 1938
  - Richardson, Wayne (New York, NY), 1955
  - Rostow, Eugene (Geneva, Switzerland), 1948-1950
  - Salwen, Milly (New York, NY), 1960
  - Sanf, Michael Harris (San Francisco, CA), 1954
  - Schlamm, William (New York, NY), 1945-1946
  - Schlesinger, Arthur, Jr. (Washington, DC), 1947-1963
  - Schwartz, Charles P., Jr. (Chicago, IL), 1958
  - Seely-Brown, Horace, M. C., Jr (Washington, DC), 1961
  - Seligman, Daniel, (New York, NY), 1965
  - Shafer, Boyd C. (Washington, DC), 1956
  - Sherwood, James D. (New York, NY), 1957
  - Shimer, W. B. (Detroit, MI), 1957
  - Sievert, Norman G. (n.p.), 1962
  - Silver, Rabbi Abba Hillel (Cleveland, OH), 1928
  - Slasko, Wanda G. (New York, NY), 1944
  - Smith, Reginald Heber (Boston, MA), 1952
  - Sokolsky, George E. (Otis, MA), 1939
  - Sonnenberg, Benjamin (New York, NY), 1954
  - Stamm, T. (n.p.), 1936
  - Staudinger, Else (New York, NY), 1948
  - Taggart, Arthur F. (Scarsdale, NY), 1954
  - Thomas, Norman (n.p.), 1934
  - Thompson, Rupert C., Jr (Providence, RI), 1964
  - Tresca, Carlo (n.p.), n.d.
  - Trilling, Lionel (New York, NY), 1947, 1962
  - U.S. Office of War Information (New York, NY), 1942-1943
  - Urban, Mrs. Joseph (New York NY), 1949
  - Vagts, Mrs. Alfred (Sherman, CT), 1958
  - Vambery, Rusztem (Washington, DC), 1947
  - Van Dusen, A. C. (Pittsburgh, PA), 1958
  - Vaudrin, Philip (New York, NY), 1939
  - Vaugham, Samuel S. (New York, NY), 1962-1963
  - Von Neumann, John (Washington, DC), 1955
  - Wachsmuth, Alex (Vienna, Austria), 1950-1951
  - Walker, Adelaide (n.p.), 1933
  - Warren, Charles (Washington, DC), 1943-1946
  - Wechsler, Herbert (New York, NY), 1947
  - Wechsler, James (New York, NY), 1940
  - Weed, Clyde E. (New York, NY), 1956
  - Weissman, George (New York, NY), 1954
  - Wheeler, M. I. (New York, NY), 1944 (Box 3)
  - White, Mrs. Connie Burwell (n.p.), 1946
  - Whitney, William Dwight (New York, NY), 1952
  - Wohlforth, Robert Martin (Washington, DC), 1936-1937
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr. (Boston, MA), 1946, 1954
  - Zeligs, Meyer A., M.D. (Carpinteria, CA), 1962
  - Zellerbach, J. D. (San Francisco, CA), 1953
  - Zionist Organization of America (New York, NY), 1929-1930
  - Miscellany
- Correspondence of Sylvia Salmi Solow, 1965-1976
  - Unidentified (New York, NY), 1965 (Box 3)
  - Bell, John (Salisbury, Rhodesia), April 3, 1968
  - Brainard, Mrs. Peter B. (Wilder, VT), n.d.
  - Dupee, Fred W. (Carmel, CA), 1975
  - Hook, Sidney (Stanford, CA), 1973-1976
  - Levine, Isaak Don (Waldorf, MD), 1975-1976
  - Lohf, Kenneth A. (New York, NY), 1976
  - Trilling, Diana (New York, NY), 1976
  - Trilling, Lionel (New York, NY), 1974-1975
  - Wald, Alan (Ann Arbor, MI), 1975-1976
  - Walker, Mrs. Adelaide (Wellfleet, MA), 1975
  - Weinstein, Allen (Northhampton, MA), 1975-1976
- Speeches and Writings, 1927-1963
  - Untitled writings (Box 3)
    - Liberty of the press, unpublished editorial, March 23, 1948. Memo on the Sloan MS., unpublished, June 30, 1961. War criminals, 1st draft editorial note, September 8, 1955.
  - Titled writings
    - After Madison Square Garden, The Modern Monthly, n.d., Printed copy.
    - The All-Purpose Executive, Fortune, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Anaconda: one face to the future, Fortune, January 1955., Printed copy.
    - `Automation': News behind the noise, Fortune, n.d., Printed copy.
    - The Beards catch the true rhythm of our civilization's rise, New York Evening Post Literary Review, April 30, 1927., Printed copy.
    - The biggest capitalist in Italy, Fortune, July, 1954., Printed copy.
    - Billion Dollar Sutler, first draft, 1962., 1 photocopy (typescript).
    - Bonds across the Sea, New York Herald Tribune, April 3, 1927., Printed copy
    - The building of Nicaro, Fortune, July 1945., Printed copy.
    - The Canadian Pacific: Overdue, Fortune, August 1956., Printed copy.
    - Class war in Minnesota, The Nation, December 26, 1934., Printed copy.
    - Colleges are too cheap, Fortune, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Colonial big Five, Fortune, November 1952., 1 printed copy. 1 photocopy (negative).
    - Coming revolt in the desert, The Nation, July 2, 1938., Printed copy.
    - The Company twice as big as Rhode Island, Fortune, March, 1961., Printed copy.
    - Conflict, unpublished first draft, August 29, 1960., Photocopy (typescript).
    - Conflict of interest: A legal nightmare, Fortune, n.d., Printed copy.
    - The Congo is in business, Fortune, November 1952., Printed copy.
    - Crown Zellerbach's Second growth, Fortune, January 1954., Printed copy.
    - Defaulting States, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Delrin: du Pont's Challenge to metals, published article, Fortune, August 1959. Printed copy. Also its Russian translation under title Istoriia Delrina, published in a Soviet magazine with no title of the magazine or date of the article. Printed copy.
    - Il diritto d'asilo: il caso Beduzzi (In Italian), Il Martello, July 18, 1938., Printed copy.
    - The drillings and diggings of Dr. Phillips, Fortune, February 1957., 3 printed copies, 2 photocopies.
    - Dunning Uncle Sam, New York Herald Tribune, March 27, 1927., Printed copy.
    - The Dutch get private dollars, Fortune, September 1954., Printed copy.
    - Fascists sit on governing boards of CP Fronts as Comintern revamps American apparatus, n.d., Printed copy.
    - For the protection of experimental education, The New Republic, April 20, 1932.., Printed copy.
    - The Forceful Ferre family, Fortune, October 1959., 2 printed copies.
    - GSA: Washington's most durable mess, Fortune, August 1955., Printed copy.
    - Geochemistry: the prospector's new tool, Fortune, February 1959., 3 printed copies
    - German writers say `Yes', The Nation, January 17, 1934., Printed copy.
    - Gerritt Smith, unpublished article, nd.d, Carbon copy. (typescript)
    - Goldfine got a raw deal, Fortune, October 1958., Printed copy.
    - The Great Minneapolis strike, The New Leader, September 8, 1934., Printed copy.
    - Hardboiled rayonier, Fortune, n.d., Printed copy.
    - How NSF got lost in Mohole, Fortune, March 1963., 4 printed copies.
    - How not to award a Navy contract, Fortune, December 1960., 2 printed copies.
    - How not to conduct foreign policy: Palestine Desk, working draft, March 18, 1948., Mimeographed (typescript).
    - How to talk to machine tools, Fortune, March 1962., 2 printed copies.
    - In defense of academic freedom, correspondence item published, The New Republic, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Inco's novel problem, competition, Fortune, May, 1957., 2 printed copies.
    - Inghilterra e Italia in Palestina, published article in an Italian newspaper, n.d. Originally in the Nation., Printed copy.
    - Inland Steel does it again, Fortune, July 1958., 2 printed copies.
    - Integrity of the Supreme Court, Fortune, February 1954., Printed copy.
    - Is G. M. a better risk than the U.S.? Fortune, August 1959., Printed copy.
    - KCL's third career, First draft. January 16, 1961., Photocopy (typescript)
    - Letters from abroad: unrest in Austria, The Menorah Journal, n.d., Printed copy (Box 4)
    - La liberte d'opinion; un point de vue americain (in French), newspaper article, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Life and death of a scholar; Hedwig Hintze, 1884-1942. n.d., Carbon copy typescript.
    - A life for a life, some notes, n.d., Carbon copy transcript.
    - A little retirement, August 16, 1962, typewritten first draft.
    - The Medicine Men of Kalamazoo, Fortune, July 1959., Printed copy.
    - Mexico's problems discussed from both Mexican and American points of view - our mediavel heritage, New York Evening Post Literary Review, February 5, 1927., Printed copy.
    - Minutiae of left-wing literary history, Partisan Review, (1938?)., Printed copy.
    - Moonlighting on Capitol Hill, unpublished draft for one-part article, March 21, 1960., Photocopy typescript.
    - The network Congressman, unpublished draft typewritten, n.d., Carbon copy typescript.
    - The New York Hotel Strike, The Nation, February 28, 1934., Printed copy.
    - North American: a corporation deeply committed. Fortune, June 1962. In addition, correspondence relative to the article., 2 printed copies and related correspondence.
    - Once again: Western Unionism, Labor and Industry, November 28, 1934., Printed copy.
    - Operations research is in business, Fortune, n.d., Printed copy.
    - A political enemy of Mussolini's rule: Italy under Il Duce, and Don Luigi Sturzo, Democrat, views it, New York Evening Post Literary Review, March 26, 1927., Printed copy.
    - Private point four in Morocco, Fortune, September 1951., Printed copy.
    - The Problem of disloyalty, published newspaper article, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Profit hunters in Puerto Rico, published article, n.d., Printed copy.
    - A rather startling result, published article, n.d., Printed copy.
    - The realities of Zionism, The Menorah Journal, November-December, 1930., Printed copy.
    - Rebirth in Italy, The Memorah Journal, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Refugee scholars in the United States, The American Scholar, Summer, 1942.
    - Research report: Revere's ride, unpublished report, (June?) 1940., Carbon copy (typescript)
    - The ripe problems of United Fruit, Fortune, March 1959., 2 printed copies.
    - Royal Little's remarkable retirement, Fortune, October 1962., Printed copy.
    - Science for sale at a profit, Fortune, March 1955, Printed copy and relative correspondence.
    - So they did business with Samish, Fortune, April 1954., 2 printed copies.
    - Soft coal: how strong a comeback, Forutne, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Solow corrects Bishop story on `Peace League', published newspaper article, December 1939., Printed copy.
    - Mr. Solow thinks otherwise, The Nation, February 7, 1934., Printed copy.
    - The Soviet Industry of confession manufacture, newspaper article, Alert! n.d., Printed copy.
    - Stalinites hawk old fronts for new to shield pro-Nazi line, The New Leader, July 27, 1940., Printed copy.
    - Stalin's ambassador keeps his head, unpublished article, n.d., Carbon copy (typescript).
    - Stalin's great American hoax: the League for Peace and Democracy, The American Mercury, n.d., 3 printed copies.
    - Stalin's secrets, editorial, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Stalin's spy scare, - American edition, unpublished article, n.d., Carbon copy (typescript).
    - Story safari, short article, Fortune, September 1951., Printed copy.
    - Substitution, at left tackle: Hemingway for Dos Passos, Partisan Review, n.d., Printed copy.
    - Sweatshops in the home, The Nation, December 2, 1939., Printed copy.
    - The techniques of Communism, The American Teacher, May, 1941., Photocopy (negative) of printed copy.
    - Those resourceful Greek shipping men, Fortune, October 1953., Printed copy.
    - Three-way payoff in Liberia, Fortune, April 1953., Printed copy.
    - Troyanovsky keeps his head, unpublished typewritten article, n.d., Carbon Copy (typescript)
    - TV payola on Capitol Hill, Life article, 2d draft, February 15, 1960., Photocopy (typescript).
    - The Unholy Alliance; how the Kremlin game of power politics played into Hitler's hand, n.d., 2 printed copies.
    - Union-smashing in Sacramento; the truth about the Criminal Syndicalism Trial, pamphlet, August 1935., 2 printed copies.
    - U.S. Foreing Policy, 1st draft, n.d., Mimeographed (typescript).
    - U.S. may ship anti fascist to death, newspaper article, July 30, 1938., Printed copy.
    - Visas to freedom, December 20, 1956., Carbon copy (typescript).
    - Voltaire and some Jews, The Menorah Journal, n.d., Printed copy.
    - War in Minneapolis, The Nation, August 8, 1934., Printed copy.
    - What next in Scottsboro?, draft, 1936?, Typewritten copy.
    - What are the brain waves saying? The American Mercury, n.d. (Joint author with Dorothy Miller), Printed copy.
    - Whither the Soviet Bear, unpublished article, not present in the collection, 1939. Correspondence.
    - Who gets the sympathy?, The Open Forum, April 27, 1935., Printed Copy.
    - Who is going to clean up Micaro?, Fortune, June 1953., Printed copy.
    - Why the silence?, The Jewish Criterion, January 13, 1933., Printed copy.
    - A year of the Stalin-Hitler pact, manuscript, n.d., Carbon copy (typescript).
    - Book reviews, published in: The Menorah Journal, The Nation, The New Republic, The New York Evening Post Literary Review, The Social Frontier, and others, 1927-1938., Printed copies.
  - Miscellany., Printed and carbon copies (typescript).
- Subject File, 1930-1964.
  - Air bases, American - Morocco. Published articles, reports, correspondence, and newspaper clippings, 1951-1958. (Box 5)
  - Alderman, Sidney S., Background and highlights of the Nuernberg Trial, published in I.C.C. Practioners' Journal, November, 1946., Typewritten copy.
  - American Council of Learned Societies Project, Research into the Marxist experience of three American literary intellectuals: Herbert Solow, John Wheelwright, Sherry Mangan., 1 typewritten copy and 3 photocopies.
  - Antarctic treaty. The New York Times, October 26, 1958, newspaper article
  - Anti-communism. Newspaper clippings.
  - Arab countries. Newspaper articles published in several newspapers. 1958-.
  - Arendt, Hannah, `The Deputy': Guilt by silence?, published in New York Herald Tribune, February 23, 1964., Printed copy.
  - Aron, Raymond, Second thoughts on Suez; Super-powers can defy humanity; the rest cannot even assert their own interest, The New Leader, January 28, 1957., Printed copy.
  - Badeau, John S. Islam and the modern Middle East, Foreign Affairs, n.d., Printed copy.
  - Becher, Ulrich, Ein Nachwort zum Nuernberger Prozess, La Otra Alemania, Das Andere Deutschland, December 10, 1946., Printed copy.
  - Berger, Elmer, What doth anti-Zionism require of thee: to understand, to evaluate, to interpret, address at the American Council of Judaism, 18th Annual Conference, Chicago, IL., May 10, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Berle, A. A. Jr., Our role in Latin America, The Reporter, November 23, 1961., Printed copy.
  - Berlin Wall
  - Biow, Milton H. and the Biow Company. Reports and notes, 1953-1954., Typewritten and printed copies.
  - Bissell, Richard.
  - Black, Justice Hugo L. Newspaper article, Black doubts suits for libel and legal, by Anthony Lewis, The New York Times, June 11, 1962., Printed copy.
  - Blakeney, Major Ben Bruce. International military tribunal, American Bar Association Journal, August 1946., Typewritten copy.
  - Borchard, Edwin, International law and international organization,n.d., Carbon copy (typescript).
  - Brodersen, Arvid, Soviet Social Science and our own, Social Research, Autumn, 1957., Printed copy.